see ladies and gentlemen a very warm
welcome to ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited q1 fy24
earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bhargav Das Gupta MD and CEO
of the company
Mr gopal balachandran CFO and cro
Mr Sanjeev mantri executive director and
Mr alok Agarwal executive director
please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involved risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to defer materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in listen only mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your Touchstone phone
I now run the conference over to Mr
barkavadas Gupta MD and CEO ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited thank
you and over to you sir
thank you and good evening to each one
of you
thank you for joining the earnings
conference call of ICC Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited for q1 fi 2024
I will give you a brief overview of the
industry Trends and developments that we
have witnessed in the past few months
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter ended June
30 2023.
India's real GDP growth recorded a
strong stronger growth than estimates
and has surprised the pre-pandemic
levels domestic demand conditions remain
supportive of growth on the back of
improving household consumption and
investment activity
Urban demand remains resilient with
indicators such as passenger vehicle
sales and domestic and passenger traffic
posted overs gold on a year-on-year
basis
this growth can have some impact on
headwinds such as weak external demand
volatility Global Financial conditions
and prolonged geopolitical tensions
for the quarter as per data published by
CM the new vehicle sales continue to
grow year on year for private currently
Village however the growth narrowed in
the month of June uh this year the
growth in sales commercial vehicle was
at a double digit during the quarter two
wheeler sales to the quarter in terms of
volumes remained below the pre-pandemic
levels health insurance continued to
remain the largest contributor to
overall growth the commercial lines
witnessed growth in line with the
current market environment
while the fire Market has seen some rate
sessions the inherent growth remains
intact
the focus of the government on
infrastructure has led to a 41.3 growth
during q1 of FY 2024 in the engineering
line of business and it's expected to
show encouraging growth in the future as
well
we remain optimistic that the industry
will continue to grow given Federal
favorable macros regulatory changes low
penetration and positive consumer
sentiment
speaking of the performance The General
insurance industry delivered a gdpi
growth of 17.9 for q1 of this year
overall the underwriting performance
improved with a combined ratio the
industry at 115.8 for F5 2023 as it is
109.1 for fi 2022
for motor business the combined ratio
for the industry remained elevated at
121.1 for fi 2023 up from 115.6 for f by
2022 combined ratio for motor and H1 of
F5 2023 was 123.5 which improved to
118.8 for H2 of fy23
moving to radically updates the
authority on June 30th 2023 published
guidelines for remuneration of
non-executive directors and Key
Management personal prescribing limits
on demonstration age engineer
moving to business impact for us in q1
2024 the company grew by 18.9 as
compared to the industry growth of 17.9
excluding crop the company grew by 19.2
percent as against the industry growth
of 17.4 percent
go for key segments during the quarter
in Property and Casualty line of
business we grew at 17.0 which is which
is higher than the industry growth of
7.8 percent
further during the quarter we accredited
market share across all segments such as
fire Marine engineering and liability
discontinuance discontinuation of the
iib rates had a moderate impact which is
in line with our expectations however we
will continue to monitor the development
in coming quarters
in motor the growth was kept at 5.3
percent for the quarter while we grew at
10.8 in June
while we witnessed further we witnessed
month-on-man growth in uh new Private
Car segment during the quarter
with no motor TV price hike we have
rebalanced our portfolio result in a
commercial vehicle makes at 21 and two
wheeler makes at 30.3 percent for q1 of
24.
the health segment continued to be the
fastest growing segment for the industry
during the quarter we grew at 40.4
percent Which is higher than the
industry growth of 20.7 percent
in group health employer employee
segment the change in underlying
industry pricing sentiment resulted in
customers moving towards customers
towards companies with better
underwriting and service capabilities
resulting in our group health segment to
grow by 43.9 percent during the quarter
as a result of a continued investment in
retail Health distribution we have
outgrown the industry growth of 18 in q1
24 with the growth of 22.8 percent this
was driven by business source through
retail health agency vertical growth of
25.6 percent
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop
solution for all insurance and wellness
need I'll take care app has surpassed
5.6 million user downloads till date the
incremental download for the quarter was
close to 1 million for q1 of this year
the premium sourced through I'll take
care contributed 58 or 588.0 million to
the gdpi reflecting a five times your
increase
our bank issues in key relationship
group uh grew at 27.3 percent this
quarter post pandemic steady credit
growth along with deep Mining and
increase in volunteer and distribution
Partners has been the key go driver
overall our digital Focus has enabled us
to increase our digital revenues
including I'll take care app revenues to
3.12 billion rupees which are conspired
accounts for 4.9 percent of our overall
gdpi for the quarter
we continue to make significant
investments in modernizing our
technology architecture after moving to
the cloud in fi 2022 we modernized a
number of our front-end applications
being on the cloud and transitioning to
to Cloud native has led to increase in
reliability for technology platforms as
evidenced by the reduction in air
tickets by error tickets by closest 71
this year
in the last year at the same time we
have seen an 86 reduction in response
times across all of our digital channel
partners
our you know responsible intelligent
assistant we call Riya our chatbot has
enabled our DIY adoption by 3.4 times
over 13 month period
alongside transitioning to the cloud and
modernization we completed the migration
of applications and data from the
hospital bharti extra data center to our
application platforms and cloud data
center in just 14 months we believe that
this was one of the fastest migrations
of this scale in the insurance industry
globally
you also continue to remain focused on
leveraging our digital capabilities and
building claims efficiency
case in point towards model claim
settlement process we introduced Cloud
calling features enabling over two lab
customers during the quarter to connect
seamlessly using a dedicated virtual
number 81 of our customers file e-clean
form in q1 24 up from 67 in q1 of last
year in q1 24 through our PPN Network
the preferred payment garage Network we
were able to service 60 of our non-oem
claims up from 40 in q123 residently our
overall NPS for non-cashless claims
improved to 62 percent uh for the year
till May 2020. see up from 42 for q1 of
23. also NPS for cashless claims
increased improved to 68 for YTD May 23
up from 60 in q1 of last year
to conclude I would like to summarize
that we are well positioned for the
future we remain focused on growth
levels such as Innovation digital
advancements launching new products
strengthening our distribution engine
rationalizing cost while scaling up our
preferred lines of business
I will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
Recently concluded quarter thanks markup
and good evening to each one of you I
will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for q1 fy24 we have uploaded the results
presentation on our website you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers
premium income of the company was at
63.87 billion rupees in q1 fy24 as
against 53.70 billion rupees in q1 f523
a growth of 18.9 percent against
industry growth of 17.9 percent
excluding crop gdpr growth as a company
was at 19.2 percent which was higher
than the industry growth of 17.4 percent
in q1 fy24
our gdpi growth was primarily driven by
growth in the preferred segments the
overall gdpi growth of our Property and
Casualty segment grew by 17 at rupees
22.86 billion in q1 Empire 24 as against
rupees 19.54 billion in q1 fy23 on the
retail side of the business GDP of the
motor segment was at rupees 18.75
billion in q1 fy24 as against rupees
17.82 billion in q1 f523 registering a
growth of 5.3 percent
our aging including the point of sale
distribution count was at one lakh
seventeen thousand one Forty Nine as on
June 30 2023 up from around 1 lakh
thirteen thousand as on March 31 2023
the advanced premium was rupees 32.63
billion as at June 30 2023 as against
rupees 32.17 billion as at March 31 2023
resultantly combined ratio was 103.8
percent for q1 fy24 as against
104.1 percent for q1 fy23 excluding the
impact of cyclone losses Cyclone losses
of 0.35 billion rupees the combined
ratio was 102.9 for q1 fy24
the technical reserves which are
presented as a part of the reserving
disclosures are not discounted as per
the current regulatory framework
however globally we understand
technically reserves technical reserves
are presented on a discounted basis
if we were to Discount the technical
Reserve particularly for the long tail
businesses such as motor third party
which constitutes around 80 percent of
our total outstanding and ibnr Reserves
our current reported combined ratio of
104.5 for FY 2023 would look better by
around 400 basis points
our investment assets Rose to rupees
449.05 billion as a June 30 2023
from rupees 431.8 billion as at March 31
2023 our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.16 times as at June 30
2023 as against 4.15 times as at March
30 on 2023 investment income was at
rupees 8.23 billion in q1 f524 as
against rupee 6.55 billion in q1 f523
our capital gains stood at rupees 1.23
billion in q1 fy24 as against rupees
0.32 billion in q1 fy23 our profit
before tax grew by 11.8 percent at
rupees 5.2 billion in q1 fi 24 as
against rupees 4.65 billion in q1 f523
consequently profit after tax grew well
11.8 rupees 3.90 billion q and fy24 as
against rupees 3.49 billion in q1 f523
continued to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5 times as I
conclude I would like to reiterate we
continue to stay focused on driving
profitable growth sustainable value
creation and safeguarding interest of
policyholders at all times I would like
to thank you for attending this earnings
call and we will now be happy to take
any questions that you may have thank
you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue you may press star
and two
participants are requested to use a
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question qscend is
[Applause]
we have a first question from the line
of Praise Jain from motilal oswal please
go ahead
uh yeah I agree everyone this is a few
few questions uh firstly couldn't talk
us through the loss ratios like uh so X
catastrophic what would be the loss
ratios and uh where is this loss ratio
kind of setting so you know if I look at
a group health loss ratio or a totally
Health loss ratio is at 78.7 percent
could you split that up for us or you
know in terms of core retail retail
health and grouping and where it is
catastrophic loss exactly stepping in
which line item
we told the segments
the fresh
insofar as the breakup of the overall
health loss ratio numbers that you see
which is 78.7 for q1 fi 24 the breakup
of that for employer employee or the
group health is at about 92.6 percent
the retail indemnability business is at
about 64.2 percent so that's the breakup
for the overall health
and to your other question in terms of
where is the impact of cyclone gnosis
largely sitting upon it is predominantly
in the property and the casualty line of
businesses which is In The Fire And
Engineering line of businesses
predominantly a very small proportion of
claims is there in motor but
predominantly a large part of the impact
on the Cyclone is in Fire and
Engineering the combined impact as what
we give at the part of the opening
remarks for this quarter the net impact
of claims on account of cyclone losses
has been about 35 crores okay but any
reason for this for a very high loss
pressure on the group side is there a
weekend some number of planes or
frequency or severity
so no specific in general if you see
what we have been speaking about prayers
even in the past on the employer
employee segment generally we have
spoken about the loss ratios to stay in
the range of around that 95 kind of
threshold between 90 to 95. because it
primarily compressed comprises of two
books as what we have spoken one is
relatively large corporates which kind
of runs at a loss ratio anywhere ranging
between 95 to 100 and then we have the
relatively SME which is a small and
limit corporate portfolio which runs in
the loss ratio experience between 90 to
95. so on balance threshold
currently for the quarter assistant the
number stands at about 92.6 so hence to
that extent no specific changes when we
see in the context of whether let's say
an increase in frequency or increase in
severity with respect to claims
we don't see any uh any significant
pressure on the health illustration side
retail isn't performing well and group
health because the cost of acquisition
is low uh this is typically where the
loss issue land
you got that and coming to motor segment
you know from again from a
profitability perspective and the mix
that you have change of mix that you've
spoken about to going away from
commercial vehicles would that be a
strategy for fi 20s or uh or from a
longer term perspective and secondly
could you talk about you know like for
many quarters we've spoken about some
green shoots on the Audi pricing uh but
you know that's that's not really
reflecting very heavily in terms of
numbers while you mentioned about the
industry loss ratios kind of combined
ratios kind of Dick improving between
first half and second half is there any
more clear trends that you know you see
further Improvement or it's just you
know kind of getting arrested at the
current levels
so on the first one commercial vehicles
uh I think some of the uh granular calls
that we took certain strategy because
then we took over the last two to three
years which we've talked about I think
we are kind of staying invested with
this with that uh the bit of
rationalization that we did was because
the TP price hike this year didn't
happen so with our estimate of inflation
as we've already always talked about
then certain marginal portfolios being
becoming become unbearable having said
that if you see your 21 percent it's
still higher than what our traditional
TV markets mix had been which was about
15 16 and our sense is that we are not
planning to reduce the signature it will
probably be in the similar ballpark uh
you know 20 plus minus uh coming to your
uh coming to a question on OD again if
you look at uh this quarter lost issue
for us on the OD compared to last year
uh you see a Improvement yeah having
said that the expectation that we've had
is some of the aggression on sourcing
side given the expensive management will
cap the flexibility to some of the
players we would we were expecting some
more rationalization some more
Improvement at this point in time we've
not seen it but I think you're kind of
reached a level where we've ironed out
most of the marginal portfolios so most
of the pain is behind us as we think
okay
foreign
thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to answer
queries from all participants please
restrict your questions to two at a time
you may join by the queue for follow-up
questions
we'll take our next question from the
line of sanket godam from Avengers Park
please go ahead
yeah thank you for the opportunity uh my
question is around the water only
businesses if I look at the numbers uh
consistently it has been improving from
second quarter or first quarter of fie
23 the number is around 67. so just
wanted to understand that this number of
67 is sustainable or or or actually want
to understand more in detail what what
corrective measures you have taken so
that so that except for except for the
choice of not seizing the market share
which has led to the Improvement in the
into Improvement in the loss ratio in
the motor segment Audi segment rather uh
that's one one thing
and how much it can potentially
contribute to the entire entire gwp As
Time progress
the multiple things that we've been
doing and you know in a sense we've been
saying that a lot of you know heavy
lifting we did last year uh one is the
selection uh the marginal portfolios
you've let go that has an impact
so our sourcing or this is the target
loss issue when we source of business
that is also come out the second is on
the claim side there's been a huge
amount of effort that we have done more
in terms of uh some of the abuse that
was that that generally happens but we
believe had picked up post covet so on
the claims control we've done a lot of
work on using data analytics uh to
reduce waste and abuse uh thirdly we
talked about the percentage increase in
PPL that also gives us some Savings of
the claim site so there are multiple
initiatives that has happened and you
know is this sustainable again we'll
have to wait to see Market conduct but
we are reasonably hopeful that we should
be able to sustain this at this current
level
uh coming to your point on I'll take
care the number that we gave out it's
about five times from last year's
similar number for the quarter but in
aggregate for the company even if we add
this I'll take a number to the overall
digital business it's as we said it's
about 4.9 percent of our of our total
business let's say I'll take care of a
contribution for this quarter was about
58 crores 588 million so it's got a
material number as yet but we believe
this is actually helping us at multiple
levels one is uh customer engagement
retention we see some loss you know
better lost ratio for clients which use
I'll take care in group levels we see a
better retention of you know profitable
accounts
strategically in terms of increasing uh
crosstal and upsell uh that's a working
progress but still honestly in terms of
aggregate numbers we are very heartened
by the scale uh the speed at which is
speaking up but still small in the
overall scheme of things
just about one one clarification
is this I will take care of you are able
to manage causal predominantly retail
Health at 58 crores or 59 crores or or
it is it is other products also you have
seen attraction
is you are seeing two wheelers we are
seeing Health we are seeing uh you know
uh more you know private car we are
seeing uh employees of uh you know
corporates buying policies uh on their
own so it's a mix of uh most products
that we have there
got it got it and finally last one gopal
if you can explain the uh the the reason
why the commission cost has boosted
overall expense has not changed but but
the commission cost has gone up but but
expense has come down so so you have
seen that um impact already visible with
respect to shifts from advertising cost
to the commission
I think to look at the businesses from
an overall combined perspective
because as we keep saying there are
different models of sourcing that exist
in the market I mean there are segments
which relatively run on ilr and low
expense of management and and the other
way around
so which is what now when you look at
let's say even from a quarter one
perspective I think I would kind of
always keep urging to look at it more
from an expensive management standpoint
rather than looking at any breakups
around that so if you look at the
overall expense of management in terms
of the breakup of the combined ratio
that we reported about 103.8 percent for
quarter one of which the loss ratio was
about 74.1 percent and the balance which
is almost about 29.7 percent is the
expensive Management number this if you
look at it for quarter one of last year
the expensive Management number was
about 32.1 percent
and again when you look at it even
vis-a-vis quarter four quarter four the
expensive Management number was about
29.9 so even on a sequential basis I
think we have seen an improvement in the
overall expenses management and even on
a year on year this is I think clearly
there have been an improvement in the
overall expense of management that's the
way we would want you to look at because
as I said there are different models of
sourcing that exist and and as a company
that's what you would want to kind of
look at thanks
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
nidesh Jain from investec please go
ahead
uh thanks for the opportunity
uh if you break the digital business so
what percentage of business is coming
from our own website plus I'll take care
and how are the trends in that segment
why on a YY basis
so if you look at the railway uh manage
this business there is uh the digital
one team which looks at if you remember
we had said there are two uh objectives
that we they have one is uh the website
business growth the other is working
with the digital ecosystem partners
and we look at it together that that's
good for this quarter is about 37.8 uh
the I'll Take Care number as you said is
relatively small but that's grown from a
small base at five times
you know that's 400 percent
if you look at the annual disclosure I
think last year uh in public disclosure
the data indicates that uh the growth
from our own website has not been that
strong it has been letting out uh growth
is largely coming from the digital
ecosystem so are those Trends continuing
in this quarter also or uh and because
the business coming from our own website
will be much more uh much more better
quality low uh much more profitable
probably over a period of time so uh how
will you think about the strategy on the
digital side website
so obviously we look at all of them are
preferred channels of sourcing whether
you look at business through website
business through alliances and even
let's say the I'll take care opportunity
as what uh balgaam explained for us all
the three segments have grown uh whether
you look at it from a site standpoint
whether you look at it even from an
alliance standpoint in fact during the
quarter we have further strengthened the
number of alliances types that we have
and that's the reason why that part is
that that part of the business has done
uh phenomenally quite well and overall
as we said the digital one contribution
in terms of revenue for the company for
this quarter has grown at about 24.7
percent
so secondly uh last year we put out a
strategy that we will focus on higher
loss ratio and low Opex ratio business
in the motor only segment uh so how
while if you look at that loss ratios
have improved uh quite a bit and Opex
ratio has also seen some improvement uh
so how is the uh how is the trend there
where the uh how the share of that
business is shipping up on overall Moto
gdpi
it's okay again again uh again it's a
combination of both sidesh is what I
would say I think what we put out as a
part of our opening remarks I think for
us if you look at this particular
quarter I think the growth on new
private car has kind of come back uh
which is kind of exhibited when you look
at it sequentially on a month-old basis
I think the growth in new private cars
seems to be kind of doing well having
said and that typically also comes with
a relatively better loss experience
having said that I think we are also
kind of increasingly focusing on exactly
the point that you mentioned with
respect to focusing on relatively older
vehicle segments which also comes with a
relatively High LR and let's say a lower
cost of acquisition and that's again
reflecting also in the extensive
Management number and if you recollect
what we have been talking about
historically our proportion of motor
business coming in through the OEM
channel of contribution used to be in
the range of 75 to 80 percent
increasingly that proportion of
contribution of business of motor coming
in from let's say the OEM Channel
distribution is will be in the range of
about 60-65 percent
actually I think what we have been
trying to do is to balance the overall
personal
between
contribution from OEM dealership agency
as well as the earlier point that we
made in terms of the digital
opportunities advances
that's it for my side thank you
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
Shreya Shivani from clsa please go ahead
yeah hi thank you I have two questions
first is on the motor segment a total
motor segment so uh if I compare uh
Lombard's both loss ratio and growth
across the private peers I would
specifically look at the private General
insurance so many of them would have
just a few percentage Point higher loss
ratio on this segment but they are
they're delivering about
you know 15 growth uh in this quarter as
per the AI data so what can be what can
we expect for Lombard uh Lombard's motor
segment for the full year and any
guidance on the over overall premium
growth for fy24 FY 24 that's the first
question and uh the second question is
uh on the crop loss ratio it seems a
little higher uh at more than 100
percent and last year I remember you
guys had shared that
um the crop program that you had
participated in was a 80 120 cap plan
something like that so so if you can
help us understand that
so so the second part is any kind of
answer uh answer that Shreya so in
general if you recollect uh obviously
the claim development Cycle takes time
and that's the reason uh from a
conservical standpoint whenever we book
the revenues
given that we don't have complete
experience of loss development we end up
providing it to 100
loss ratio basis so which is why when
you look at that numbers uh you will
find the lost ratios to be a bit
elevated but when you when the actual
experience starts to kind of play out
you will obviously start getting that
reflector on actuals so hence we and
typically it roughly takes about two
quarters for the loss development to
play out in the crop segment so as and
when we get to see the impact of the
cycle we will kind of actualize those
numbers
your first point on what is it that we
can expect on overall growth for the
company as a whole I think in line with
what we have spoken uh as we always keep
saying the market needs to get better in
terms of pricing uh at this point of
time if you have seen for quarter one I
think we have had almost close to almost
about 200 basis points South performance
the relative to the market growth
numbers when you look at X of crop uh
and so that's clearly the expectation
that we have at the company we have we
have the necessary strength in so far as
distribution claim service and
technology is concerned and ends to that
extent from an overall
Market standpoint we would obviously
want to expect us continuing to have
similar kind of uh out performance now
within that your first point on how does
one see on motor as I said again when
you look at it on sequential basis month
on month I think clearly we have been
able to possibly arrest the extent of uh
degrowth that we had seen in that
particular segment so for example in
April we had a d growth in a motor for
the month of May we had a positive
growth about five percent and for the
month of June we had a growth of almost
about 10 so frequency I think we have
been able to kind of get better and the
extent of gap between the industry
growth numbers and let's see the growth
that we have been exhibiting is kind of
getting narrowed down
the only thing that would watch out for
to your point on what we could expect
for the rest of the year is
the the adherence to the extensive
management guidelines
that's coming to post from this year in
fact I was just when we were looking at
the FI 23 numbers that's now out for the
entire Market as a whole almost close to
two-thirds of the industry participants
have their expense or Management number
greater than the regulatory prescribed
limit of 30 or 35 percent
uh so this clearly costs for an action
which is what I presume even the
regulator would be significantly uh
putting a focus on once all companies
start putting out their q1 numbers I'm
sure they will start looking at the
expense of Management number for the
overall Market as a whole and within
that each individual companies in terms
of how they are exhibited and once some
of these things starts to correct uh
over the period of time obviously as I
said so far as our positioning is
concerned I think we should be able to
kind of uh see a relatively better
growth uh even in motor essay category
[Music]
you see certain patterns I mean you know
you can do the analysis yourself and in
third party uh again if you do a bit
deeper dive on the reserving picture
which is now available to all of you
you'll be able to figure out the
reserving practices and that will
probably throw some light on the loss
ratio numbers of some of the players in
the market
got it got it so so one uh one just uh a
clarification I wanted uh the retail
Indemnity loss ratio that you mentioned
at 64.2 uh this is 64.2 for the retail
Indemnity sold by agents or the ones
which is the one which is getting sold
by ICICI Bank so not the group groups it
is the individual detailing committee
and what is the loss ratio of the ICICI
Bank
portion that is getting sold by ICICI
Bank level of detail that's not fair on
the distributor also sure sure okay
thank you
we have our next question from the line
of Rishi junjunwala from iifl
institutional equities please go ahead
yeah thanks for the opportunity this
couple of questions uh firstly on the
health side so um can you tell us about
uh you know in the you know retail has
the 23 year-on-year growth that we have
seen how much of that is driven by
pricing increase that you were taken in
February and secondly on the corporate
side there is a significant growth that
has come here
um you know is that being driven by
um you know the the normal group health
plans or there is a large component of
um you know the credit protect plans
also which are coming here and and is
that the reason why unexpired risk
Reserve has shot up quite significantly
for us in this quarter
so the second part krishi uh to your
point on the uh
one on the I'll just kind of talk about
the commercial lines as a category and
within that then I will talk about your
corporate health or let's say the uh
Group Health uh point that you wanted to
understand or across commercial lines I
think we have actually been able to
exhibit significant market share as what
we kind of also put out as a part of the
opening remarks in fact relative to an
industry growth of which is single digit
7.8 our growth has been about 17 percent
and this pans across fire Marine
engineering liability etc etc across the
key commercial line and there the growth
is aided by uh across all factors which
is it is driven by volume increase it is
equally driven by I would say uh
accretion of market share and
specifically now also in the context of
corporate Health we have also been able
to see accretion in pricing as well so
it's been an all-round kind of growth
that one has seen in the overall
commercialized portfolio
your second point on now within the
course Group Health or let's say within
the Corporate Hills again it's been a
combination of both uh we have as you
would kind of recollect uh some of the
participants in the market had exhibited
significant handwriting losses
particularly in the corporate space
and there have been clear restrictions
that they have given to their respective
operating officers to get better on
underwriting
exactly is what we kind of wait for as
opportunities for us to kind of write
businesses because as I said we have the
necessary back-end strength in terms of
distribution and let's say claim service
to our advantage so hence we have been
able to gain a great market share uh
from some of those companies into us
where customer starts to look at more in
terms of service as the basis of placing
the risk so and the growth is aided by a
Christian and market share again volume
we do see in some sectors incremental
hiring being done by some of the
corporate concerned and then to that
extent it is also volume driven and
three is also a function of as I said
the relative overall growth that one has
seen uh health is also aided by I would
say uh reasonable growth even on the
bank Insurance page as we are kind of
put out even as a part of the opening
remarks or Bank Assurance which
comprises of distribution through banks
and our key relationship group Partners
that's again done reasonably well uh at
almost about 27 growth uh on the back of
again uh reasonable growth coming back
in terms of credit uh disbursements what
one would watch for is obviously the
extent of disbursement levels as we head
into the subsequent quarters I think
that we will wait for in terms of the
development takes place
understood and second question you know
while you explained about the expensive
management thing and you know that to
look at on an overall basis and that's
anyways what we are going to do but just
from a you know purpose of understanding
uh wanted to understand the change in um
commission and the business promotion
um is it purely a reclassification issue
from books of accounts perspective from
the way you are now paying to the
distributors or is there any actually on
ground business model change also
so if you ask us
because I'm saying uh Rishi I think at
the end of the day we always look at the
overall cost of acquisition in terms of
the way we kind of
do businesses and that's the reason why
I kind of specifically put out that
number in the context of expensive
management and that's what I would urge
to kind of look at and honestly the kind
of split between what constitutes
commission what constitutes let's say My
overall operating expenses all of them
are baked in as a part of our operating
model fundamentally if you ask us have
you changed anything in so far as the
underlying way of doing business
honestly not there is no specific change
that one has kind of done and hence
which is why I'm saying that once you
start looking at the numbers more from
an expensive management standpoint
rather than trying to look at splits
between how much has been the growth in
commissions and how much has been the
changes in operating
okay thank you
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
Avinash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead
yeah hi good evening or two questions or
so first one is more on uh commercial
lines uh your particular fire
engineering so they were the sort of
multiple factors affecting the pricing
and all so just I mean if you can give
some color on that adjusting for your
Cyclone losses if there has been sort of
an impact on overall or claims ratio
because of the pricing environment or if
you can quantify also the price changes
effectively that happened in this
quarter so that's on Commercial line
second on Group Health or indoor
employee part if you can provide some
sort of you know either quantify you or
some qualitative disclosure in terms of
how has been your experience on the uh
you know uh business that you have
initially acquired a pre-covered period
and continue to renew I mean with price
hikes and the business you have acquired
or say last year so are there sort of a
difference in terms of the claims
experience in these two sets they are
two questions thank you
so uh let me take the second one and
gopal can give you the split of uh let's
say the commercialized business in the
aggregate commercial line business
there's been some uh softening on the
Fireside for the reasons that we've been
talking about which is that the iib rate
is no longer there but it's a
it's well in line with our estimates so
it's a single digit change not a
material reduction that we have seen in
the first quarter but we'll have to Be
watchful of how this progress is uh for
the rest of the year but till now it's
largely been uh you know in line with
expectations yeah the difference in me
uh you know the loss ratios for firearm
engineering without a with or without
that gopal will ask you the separency
coming back to your question on Group
Health Avinash I think the real good
news for us was that you know the
accounts that we had pre-covered uh you
know and we've been talking about this
in the past as well
uh you know from July of the year after
the first second wave we started
increasing prices by between 15 to 30
percent and we used to see almost 90
more than 90 retention of the large
accounts so I think the service
proposition that we've delivered uh you
know the the various uh features of I'll
take care Etc I think overall we've had
good experience in terms of retaining
these accounts uh this year uh for the
reasons that gopal explained we are
seeing a good Traction in business
moving from uh some of the other uh you
know companies that come coming in the
way we are pricing it is again in line
with our you know general practice of
being uh disciplined about underwriting
so the question then is that will these
guys also renew next year prices go down
that's we'll have to wait for well the
approach that we take is even when we go
in with any of these accounts we of
course used to look at customers who are
not uh you know price Seekers everywhere
who switch from one company the other
but to look at companies who generally
been stable with one insurer for some
time maybe we're wanting to move now
because of service experiences or
because pricing has significantly gone
up and come close to our numbers and we
are able to get a slight premium over
the market price so on balance I don't
see a big difference between the
accounts that we had in the past to the
accounts that we have got now on the
group also yeah and uh winners to your
point on uh what could be the potential
impact on some of this pricing LED
changes and let's say Cyclone leading
fact as part of said I think so far as
the price decline is a single digit
number roughly in that range of I would
say between five to seven percent kind
of decline in pricing is what one had
seen and that's one expected lines
that's what we had mentioned even during
the April earnings call at the time when
this guidelines had come into force uh
which is the reason why if you see for
overall Market fire grows for quarter
one is far more rapid at let's say at
5.9 or six percent uh even despite that
if you look at for ICC Lombard we can
add an out performance in that category
uh we have grown it almost about ten
percent in uh fire as a line of this so
that's the impact in so far as pricing
is concerned on the other part what we
discussed even in the April earnings
call if you recollect is also the
hardening of the insurance rates and
therefore to that extent we also had
seen an improve increase in the XML cost
what effectively happens is the NEP does
a catch up because typically your cost
of XML starts to treat you in quarter
one and as the book kind of grows the
earnings play through over the remaining
quarters so now when you look at the
loss ratios what is put out in the
investor debt for fire let's say at
about 85 for quarter one and let's say
98.6 percent
engineering now this has the impact of
the excellent cost it also has the
impact of I would say losses from
Cyclone as what I kind of mentioned it's
very difficult to kind of separately
call out the impact of the external cost
but if I were to just exclude the impact
of cyclone losses the loss ratio on fire
which is at about 85 percent will look
like about 64 65 percent and Engineering
which is looking like about 98.6 percent
will look like about uh close to about
80 82 percent uh in that range so that's
the kind of numbers that once these in
so far as excluding the fat losses are
concerned but as I said q1
particularly for engineering is
relatively more long tail as the project
starts to kind of build over a period of
time is where you will see a relatively
larger proportion of earnings coming
through and still attraction you will
always find possibly the q1 loss ratios
to be a bit more secure
okay okay yeah so I mean on Group Health
broadly I can expect that the 90 broadly
is for your old book as well as new book
I mean there is no differential
experience I requested to join by the
queue sir as there are other
participants waiting
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
swarnap Mukherjee from bnk Securities
please go ahead
yeah hi sir thank you for the
opportunity uh so couple of questions uh
first on the retail health so some you
mentioned around 64-ish loss ratio in
the retail Indemnity portfolio
um I just I was just wondering that
historically you have told that you have
run this book at around 7 loss ratios
between 65 to 70 percent so is there a
possibility that will push the pedal a
little bit more in terms of growth going
ahead so that we are in between that
Mark because profitability wise I think
we are much better than where we were
running the business so whether we
should expect to see growth panning out
at a faster rate and uh you know much
much more higher than the industry even
that our market share is still lower
than whatever company average market
share is across categories so that is
the first question on retail uh and I'm
the second question of on the fire loss
ratios you pointed out that there are
xol losses that are baked in right now
just wanted to understand that is there
you know given that elevated loss ratio
there that you have reported uh if uh if
we were to remove the impact of xol
losses also uh how should we also see so
many element of uh that deregulation
playing out in the loss ratio in terms
of uh uh you know uh denominator being
lower for from the pricing point of view
and thirdly on on the crop premium for
uh the month of June I think there was a
sizeable crop premium so that pertains
to Maharashtra and of a similar
structure of what it was done last year
let me let me add to the fire let me
take it to cover the rest as gopal
explained the the loss issue for those
two businesses look a bit elevated but
we are very comfortable and very happy
with the book as as he explained a big
chunk of the incremental loss is because
of cat which happens once in a while
secondly the price softening has had a
five to six percent impact not not as
big as one was worrying about so in that
sense it's a positive uh third is the
egg soil cost is an upfront cost as we
go through the year the anything keeps
secreting and the actual cost gets
spread over the whole 12 months for the
keyword looks elevated because
it's a smaller book through you know
which is kind of uh absorbing that
increment so I think overall our
Property and Casualty business we are
very happy with the way things are
progressing just to give you the overall
sense of where we see the business
follow up follow up on that the price
softening part that you mentioned five
to six percent give so in in a scenario
if the reinsurance market kind of
softens next year from where it is can
can it uh have this offering can be more
in our uh you know this is getting into
the Realms of speculation uh you know
too many factors are unknown in terms of
global reinsurance markets so there's no
point in talking about right now maybe
we can discuss this post January one
I think one is I think as we keep saying
I think which is what is there in the
numbers if you have seen on the overall
basis uh while we set our growth in
revenues has been let's say close to
about 19 uh X of crop if you would have
seen the growth in net return premium
has been almost about 23 which is a
function of let's say what we retain and
what we kind of uh reinsure but relative
to that if you would have seen the
growth in net has been only about 12
percent
uh so that's the catch-up that will
start to happen and this is not just
specific to any particular segment I
think for across segments when we kind
of exhibit growth you will start seeing
any P doing a catch up over the
subsequent quarters so which is what you
should kind of watch out for and as we
always keep saying
for us you should ideally look at
outcomes over years uh if not ideally on
a financial year basis definitely not
quarters I mean quarters will have lots
of elements attached to it and again we
will urge everyone to keep looking at
numbers more on annual basis ideally
over years because that's how the
insurance Cycles typically work so
that's just in addition to what parkov
said to your third point on the cross I
think uh pretty much similar to what we
have been talking uh which is even the
one that we have won in Maharashtra that
again operates under the 1810 model uh
which is where we are kind of clear
about what kind of risk that we want to
undertake and two as we had discussed
even during the April call potentially
there is an expectation that this year
could be in a year available and as to
that extent again from an exposure
standpoint I think we would want to be a
bit guarded and even otherwise what we
have said uh even uh earlier as well all
crop related to our overall numbers I
would definitely want to see that less
than five percent of the aggregate
annual revenues so that stand kind of
pretty much Remains the Same so your
first point on the overall retail Health
loss ratios again I mean this is quarter
one numbers right uh I think the range
that we gave is the range that we are
comfortable to kind of operate with uh
as a segment and what we are quite happy
and excited about is the fact that even
if you look at consistently since uh I
would say second half of last year uh
and even for the whole of in fact fy23
we have we have had out performance on
retail Hills visit with the market I
mean if you recollect for fi 23 our
growth was almost about 17 industry on
retailers grew at 15. even quarter one
when you look at the numbers for us
individual or retailers grew at almost
about 23 market growth was about 18 19
so again we have had our performance in
relative to the overall Market the good
news is even when you look at it in the
context of standard on health companies
our growth in quarter one has largely
been in line with the standard of Health
growth numbers as well so hence to that
extent whatever Investments that we're
doing on retail Health we are quite
excited with the way how the Investments
have played out and that's the reason
why you already start to see some small
levels of increase in market share that
we have seen which used to be sub three
percent right now we are at about close
to about 3.1 percent market share in the
retail Health uh indemability segment of
course as you rightly said there's a lot
of catch up that we have to do and ends
to that extent we will continue to stay
invested in building that distribution
force and uh and loss ratios as I said
will be more an outcome and the range is
what we kind of largely talked about q1
honestly again very difficult to comment
on one particular quarter you have to
ideally look at it more on a fully
assist
understood sir can I squeeze in a
question on Group Health I request you
to join by techusa
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
prakar Sharma from Jeffries please go
ahead
thank you and congratulations to all of
you uh just wanted to get a pulse of you
know this flooding in the northern
Indian Parts how big is the business how
should we kind of uh assess any
potential loss that's part one and just
wanted to get a sense on you know the
full year and next year combined ratio
you know expectation are we you're
sticking to our real guidance so these
were my two questions thank you
to the second uh one is easier to answer
yes we are sticking to it uh in spite of
these losses that cat losses that you
had in this quarter and the the North
Indian floods will come in the Q2
because these were not I mean even now
as we speak uh the losses are coming in
till now it doesn't look to be
significantly uh you know an area of
concern
but it's too early to call prakar I
think we will you know these what
happens in the floods is that it takes
some time for the customers to come back
and report all the claims so I don't
want to give up you know false comfort
that it's a low value catalog you'll
have to wait for some time
but whatever it is uh you know as a
company it under these losses are
significantly out of sync with the past
experiences I think we'll be we are
clear that we are staying within the
same guidance levels that we've talked
about
thanks thank you
we have a next question from the line of
Niraj toshniwal from UBS India please go
ahead yeah hi uh so given we have seen
some improvement in June and motor which
is quite interesting uh wanted to
understand the Outlook going ahead and
are we seeing uh some kind of pricing
Improvement which has happened due to
expensive management changes and uh no
hike in motor TP pricing for this year
as we said the on the second Point not
much we are expected some more
Improvement because of expensive
management uh you know constraints uh
you've seen some you know bit of
correction in terms of certain elements
of you know PA price etc for the ETC so
a lot of companies have improved some
element of the pricing but it's not to
the extent that one had you know
expected given the expense of management
as gopal explained uh you know for a
large number of companies in the sector
it's uh they are over the limit uh as of
now we've not seen a change but as we
explained we'll have to see what happens
after quarter one and how the regulator
looks at
industry numbers and Company specific
numbers so We'll Be watchful from our
perspective we are well within the limit
we have a big cushion but that's doesn't
mean that we are going to be profligated
we are focusing on building a
sustainable business
growth in motor Ola we are kind of now
uh given the momentum is coming back we
are building in
I think as I said earlier I think the
the
difficult part is behind us is what we
think so our expectation is that we
should definitely go in line with the
market for this quarter
regulator
uh any incremental color on that
so neeraj I think uh I think this is
something that we have been talking
about uh earlier as well so obviously at
an appropriate point of time I think as
we keep saying uh succession planning is
something that actively gets discussed
at the bnrc and at the board level uh
across management levels so maybe at an
appropriate time I think we will come
back uh if at all uh wherever we have to
make any necessary announcements
on that matter
I think they will announce it whenever
they are ready to announce it obviously
they'll have to wait for to get all the
approvals but they've got enough time uh
to uh to do the same as of now there we
are waiting on clearances from the
regulations
you've got it thanks
Thank you Rich thanks thank you
ladies and gentlemen that was the last
question for today Aina and the
conference over to Mr barkada's Gupta
for closing comments over to you sir
thank you thank you everyone for joining
uh and look forward to uh you know be
interacting with you over the next few
days feel free to reach out to us thank
you again thank you so much thank you on
behalf of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance company that concludes this
conference thank you for joining us and
even our disconnect your lines